本作品由 NORM 荣誉出品
下载后仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业途径
压制：KingX_Chin  双显&特效字幕：KingX_Chin
你们谁还要咖啡呀？
Who still wants coffee?
谢谢 给我加一点
Thank you I need a little
谢谢
Thank you
校长
Principal
这群大圈 真是一流
These Chinese gangsters are terrific
打过仗拿过勋章 是真正的人民英雄
They went through wars and got medals, real heroes
这个是老大叫大兵
This is their head, Bin
这个叫阿火
This is Fire
我们再次为争取自由 而死去的勇士们
For those who died for freedom
默哀五分钟
We are to remain silent for 5 minutes
校长 有个叫David Wong的 总警司想见你
Principal, a Superintendent Wong wants to see you
I'am sorry 打扰你们祷告
I'm sorry to interrupt your pray
黄警司 我们很忙啊
Officer Wong, we are very busy
我比你更忙
I am more busy then
全香港的警察现在 二十四小时standby
All police are on alert 24 hours
全是你们这些无聊汉害的
this is all brought by you!
我刚刚收到密报
I've just received information
有些不良分子想趁着大游行捣乱
Some gangsters want to make use of the demonstration
今天我来是想跟你商量一下
I come today to discuss with you
沿途的保安措施
About the security en route
你不介意吧
You don't mind?
我想中国人不会这么没有良心吧？
I don't believe Chinese will do such things.
那是什么？
What's that?
这些全是一级通缉犯
They are all most wanted convicts
你拿他们的相片干什么？
Why are you holding their photos?
我警告你们
I warn you guys
你们这些读书人千万别打什么主意
You lousy students mustn't think astray
怎么？想请雇庸兵去杀李鹏吗？
Why, you want to hire someone to kill Li Pang?
我们想帮助警方来逮捕他们
We just want to arrest them for you
拿个好市民奖
And get a good Citizen Award
至于大圈帮这件案子 是我自己调查的
I've been in charge in this case
我发誓 我一定要抓到这些人
I swear to God that I must arrest them
如果让我知道你们 跟他们有联络的话
If I know you are related with them
我就告你们知情不报
I'll charge you of not informing me
包庇通缉犯！
And cover up for the convicts!
黄警司 你恐吓我呀？
Officer, are you threatening me?
我吓大的 中国人是有骨气的
I won't be the least threatened!
我连北京政府都不怕 怕你啊？
I don't even fear Peking Government, so not you!
你疯啦？
Are you crazy?
你疯啦！
校长 不要那么冲动
Principal, don't act rashly
这是我衷心的话
From the bottom of my heart
虽然我是半个中国人
Though I'm half Chinese
可是我也很同情这些学生
I sym0athize these students
这是我捐的！
This is my donation
欢迎
Welcome
几位呀？
How many are you?
哥 你说呢？
Brother, what do you say?
俺说 就是他
I say, that is him.
大哥
Boss
他才是大哥
He is the boss.
对不起
Sorry.
大哥 我是欧阳卓
Boss, I am Au Yiang Chek
大哥幸会
Nice to meet you, boss.
大哥 你好吗？
How are you, boss?
我是欧阳卓 声援会的主席
I'm Au Yiang Chek, Chairman of Aiding Student Group
相信大家都知道这个会
You all know this is a group
是代表全香港的市民
Which represents all people of HK
为了解救中国千千万万的同胞
To save all Chinese people
争取民主自由
And help them get democracy and freedom
欧阳校长 我们来
Principal, this time we come
不是要参加民主歌声献中华的
Not for the fund raising concert
对不起！所有的中国人
Sorry, all Chinese people
都为了六四事件而觉得万分悲痛
Are mournful for June 4th event
我是代表声援会呼吁几位大哥
I now urge you fellows
伸出正义之手帮一个忙
To do us a favour
我们做事只谈钱
We work only for money
要我们做些什么 直说好了
Just tell us what we are to do
不用兜圈子！
And don't beat the bush
我是希望你们到广州
I hope you to go to Canton
去接应一批学生领袖来香港
To take some student leaders to HK
你们肯出多少钱？
How much will you pay?
每跑一趟二十万
Two hundred thousand each time
现在那些学生
At this moment the students
被北京政府定性为反革命暴乱份子
All classified anti-revolutionists by Peking Government
全国八百万个公安武警
Eight million of policemen
和那些特务到处在搜捕他们
And agents are locating them everywhere
这件事九死一生 没什么好处
This is a dangerous task
每跑一趟 一百万
One million dollars each time
每次限带五个人
And 5 students only
超过五个人每人补二十万
$200,000 for each additional student
开支实报实销
on you expense too!
如果你们出得起这个价钱
If you can offer us this sum
我们就开始考虑
We will start considering
起码也得要这个数啊 对不对？
At least this sum, right.
市民们捐了两千多万出来
People have donated 20 million dollars
不可能让他一个人吃光啊
So we mustn't let him use it all up
这位大哥 我希望你说话要负责任
I hope you will care about your words
我欧阳卓顶天立地
I'm a righteous man
为了民运就算倾家荡产
For pro-democracy campaign
抛头颅 洒热血 也在所不辞
I'm willing to pay and die too
这些捐款是作为长期斗争的经费
This donation is for the prolonged struggle
而你们提出来的价钱是不合理的
And the sum you ask is unreasonable
我大胆的说一句这是趁火打劫
I daresay you are robbing us
对不起！我们都是粗人 不太会讲话
Sorry, we are not learned, we don't know how to say
如果你嫌我们贵的话
If you think we charge too much
你可以找别人来做也一样
You can find others to help
校长 请你不要误会
Principal, you mustn't misunderstand us
试问那一个人不爱国呢？
We are all patriotic
阿火 我说了不做了嘛
Fire, don't say anymore as we quit
你还啰苏什么？
Why do you keep saying?
说清楚一点好
It's good to make it clear.
校长 你要明白
Principal, you must know
你在资本主义社会长大
You were brought up in capitalist world
你不知道？无产专政的恐怖
You won't know the horror of dictatorship
实在太可怕了 随时会有人告密的
It's really horrible as people will report about you Let's go.
走啦！来啦！
Let's go.
-再见 校长！  -你他妈的舌头真长
- Goodbye, Principal. - You are sharp tongue.
浪费口水！
You're wasting your breath only.
趴下！先帮你做后面
Crouch down, I'll do your back first.
我不做呀！
I won't do it
你先出去 我要求你立刻离开这里
Go out, I request you to leave here now
我想一个人静静的想点事 谢谢！
I want to think over by myself, please.
神经病！
Nut!
照上星期天的经验来看
From last Sunday situation
大游行的先头部队会在三点钟
At 3 o'clock, the first demonstration group
到达轩尼诗道
Will reach Hennessey Road
我们应该在四点钟 准时到达力生球宝行
And we should arrive Lison Jewellery Shop at 4 sharp
整个行动的时间只有三分钟
And there's only 3 minutes for our action
就是说在四点零三分
That means at 4:03
我们必需从后门撤退
We must retreat from the back door
经过小巷子 到达美心餐厅的后面
And pass the lane to back door of Maxim Restaurant
然后 举起我们预先 收藏在那边的标语
Then we will take out our flags already hidden there
转到轩尼诗道
And turn to Hennessey Road
混入游行队伍 高叫口号
And mix into the people, shouting slogans
爱国无罪 反对镇压
Against suppression!...
太好了！太好了！
Terrific...
据官方估计 明天大游行 会有一百五十万人参加
It's estimated one and a half million people will show up tomorrow
像汪洋大海一样
It's like and ocean
我们像几滴小水珠融入在里面
We'll penetrate into this big ocean
就是用电子仪器也查不出来呀
and no way to trace us anymore.
是不是？
Am I right?
这不是应了什么欧阳校长说的
Isn't this what Principal said?
什么什么趁火打劫啦！
He said we are robbing!
趁火打劫 爱国无罪！
Robbing and be patriotic!
趁火爱国 打劫无罪！
Robbing is innocent!
你懂不懂是爱国无罪呀！
Being patriotic is innocent
真笨！
Stupid!
明天的行动
About the action tomorrow
坦白说 不怕一万 就怕万一
I just fear in case...
现在报告特别新闻
Now is the special news
由于昨天晚上十二点左右
Last night at midnight
旺角有几百个举着爱国和支援民运标志的年青人
Hundreds of people holding patriotic flags
趁机滋事破坏
And pro-democrat slogans
最后聚集了几千人 演变成暴力事件
Them thousands gathered on and started a rebel
警方出动了防暴部队数百人镇压
Police had to send reinforcement to suppress
经过六小时之后才平息
It was put down only after 6 hours
警方跟支援会商量之后
After meeting the Aiding Student Group (ASG)
支援会宣布 决定取消 于明天举行的大游行
(ASG) announced to cancel the demonstration tomorrow
这他妈一下子见财化水了
Our money is gone!
这些龟孙子真他妈的无聊啊
Those lousy sly guys!
在国家民族面临重大危机的时候
At this critical moment of our country and tribe
居然还有人敢趁火打劫
They dare to rob at this moment?
你们说这多令人痛心疾首呀
Do you feel sorry about this.
真是败类！
They're lousy.
They really are.
趁火打劫都是败类
All robbers now are lousy
这样呀…我考虑一下！
In this case... I'll think over
欧阳卓找我 说愿意出到八十万！
Au Yiang Chek called me and said he'd pay $800,000
八十万？
Eight hundred thousand dollars?
一个人走起运来 这城墙都挡不住
Nothing can stop our luck flying to us
钞票拼了命往口袋里跑！
Money keeps coming to us
对 塞翁失狗！
Right, it's good luck for us
丢了一只狗 跑来一匹马
We lose a chance but other chances come
哥 这马比狗贵啊？
Brother, is this true?
是呀
Yes
那当然啦！
Of course it is
我有责任提醒你们 不怕一万 就怕万一
But I must remind you, just in case...
俺知道
Got it.
我怕钱到手也没命花
I fear I will die before getting the money
如果你们要去的话 你们去
Go yourselves if you must
不要算我
But don't count me in
走开…
Get away
儿子 我的儿子呀！
Son! My son!
谢谢…
Thanks
现在是新闻联播节目
Now is the news program
我是华润公司李言德先生 介绍我来的
Mr. Li Yin Tak of China Emporium Company recommends you to me
你是来订电子零件的吗？
You come for electronic components?
不是 我是想订电视显像管
No, I want to order TV tubes.
请进！
Please come in
哪位是负责人呀？
Who is in charge here?
我是
I am
各位手上现在拿的是 中央传达下来的档
You have a document from central in your hand
必需要传达
And it is to pass on
一式三份 要传达下去
Three to each page and must be passed on
特别是十六号
Especially number 16
袁同志 什么时候到的？
Comrade Yuen, when did you arrive?
怎么不通知我们去接飞机呀？
Why didn't inform me to greet you at the airport?
我来给你们介绍
Let me introduce you
这位是政治保卫局的袁树同志
This is Comrade Yuen from Political Defence Bureau
袁同志从北京来
Comrade Yuen, as you came from peking
是不是要传达中央的最新指示？
Are you to inform us about the lastest news from Central?
黄临同志
Comrade Wang Lin
我是奉政治局姚书记的指示来的
I was sent by Secretary Yiau of Political Division
来看看黄临你这个王八蛋
To come to see you bastard
你这个代公安局长到底是怎么当的
How you work as acting Chief?
大批民运份子逃到广州来
Many of the pro-democrats fleeing to Canton
你一个都抓不到
But you fail to arrest even one!
我来看看你是不是包庇民运份子？
I come to check if you cover up for them
袁同志 请你向姚书记解释一下
Comrade Yuen, please explain to Secretary Yiau...
我已经清楚的给你提供情报
I've clearly supplied you with information
说明王小慧这几个反党的女学生
That Wang Siu Wai and other rebellious
是躲在领事馆里面嘛！
Are hiding in embassies
进领事馆抓人 会牵涉到外交纠纷的！
But it involves diplomatic affairs if we rush into embassies to make arrestment
这件事我已经向上头报告了
I've already reported to the senior
可是到现在都没有指示
But no instruction so far.
他妈的 指示？
Shit, instruction?
什么他妈的指示呀？
What the damn instruction?
你早就应该去放火
You should have set fire on embassies
然后假装消防员冲进去
And disguised as firemen to rush in
趁乱的时候把她们统统给我抓起来
You can then arrest them in the mess!
那就是说 所有的领事馆 都要放火啦？
Must we set fire on all embassies?
你放的什么屁呀？
What shit are you talking about?
因为没有确实的情报
We don't have the exact information
不知道他们在哪一个馆里嘛！
Wo we don't know which embassy they're in
他妈的 你不会去调查调查吗？
Shit, can't you make investigation?
黄同志 革命不是请客吃饭
Comrade Wang, revolution is not to eat
不是绣花…
Or to embroider...
是…非常谢谢袁同志的教导
Yes... thanks for teaching us, Comrade Yuen
袁同志 你远道而来太辛苦了
You made all the way here
我们吃晚饭再聊吧！
So let's have a good dinner.
我家里…藏了一根 长白山的野山人参
At home... I have a superb ginseng
拿来炖果子狸很补身的！
It's excellent to make a soup.
难道你不知道中央有命令下来
Haven't you received orders from the Central
不准我们大吃大喝的吗？
That we mustn't spend too much on food?
这道菜值多少钱呀？
How much is it?
你运气好 刚好减价 才三十多块
$30 as there's a discount.
这就不同了！
This is it.
不过既然有这道菜
Since we have such a good dish
应该有瓶洋酒才行啊！
We should have some imported wine
有没有XO呀？
Is there XO?
有啊
Yes.
你的证件？
Your pass?
是！
Yes.
进去吧
Go in.
谢谢！
Thanks.
请
Please
请跟我来
Follow me
领使先生 你们这一次仗义援手
Mr. Consulat, since you help us this time
让我们知道我们并不是孤立的
We know we are not isolated
世界上面还有很多爱好自由的人仕
There are many people who love liberty
站在我们这一边
Standing by our side
我们一定会继续奋斗下去的
So we must keep on struggling
我再次代表所有的民运人士谢谢你
I thank you again on behalf of all pro-democrats
谢谢你 领使先生
Thanks. Your excellency
不用客气！
You're welcome
领使先生
Your excellency
这位是声援会派来接应你们的 义士李文先生
This is Mr. Li Wan from ASG, he's to take you away
她们三位元相信你们在电视上见过了
I think you have seen them on TV
这位是北高联的王小慧同学
Wang Siu Wai of Student joint Union
这位是陈英同学
This is Chen Yin
洪韵音同学
And this is Hung Yuen Yin
谢谢你
Thank you
别客气！
You are welcome!
在资本主义社会成长的香港人
People from capitalist HK
过去给我的印象一向是往钱看
Used to give me impression of pursuing for money
可是这一次你们对民运热烈的支持
But this time you support us whole-heartedly
却改变了我对你们香港人的印象
And changed your impression in me totally
李先生 你居然能够 冒这么大的危险
Mr. Li, you took a risk to come here
来接应我们
To pick us up
我衷心的感谢你们！谢谢！
I must thank you heartily
李先生 你跟你的朋友 来做拯救工作
Mr. Li, you and your friends are doing rescue work
真是十分英勇 我代表我国向你们致敬
You're really brave I just salute you on behalf of my country
你们放心 有我李文在的一天
Don't worry, as long as I live
我一定会尽量把王小慧 她们带到香港去
I'll try my best to take them to HK
谢谢你们的掌声！
Thank you for your applause
下车
Get out!
下车！
我们是国家安全部的
We are from National Security Bureau
把你工作证拿出来！
Show us your pass.
平常收邮件的那个人呢？
Where's the usual guy for post?
他病了！我来替他几天
He's ill and I come to substitute
如果有怀疑的话
If you have any queries
可以打电话给我单位的领导
You can phone my working place,
我不会啊要你教
I don't need you to tell me what to do
怎么样啊？对六四有什么看法？
What's your opinion of June 4th?
我对这些学生一点好感都没有
I totally dislike the students
他们破坏安定团结
They spoil the stability of our society
反对社会主义
And are ante-socialism
根本就是反革命暴乱
This is indeed anti-revolution
我不但不会窝藏他们
I won't cover them up
一发现我马上举报
I'll report once I find them.
我说过你窝藏反革命份子了吗？
Did I say you cover ante-revolutionists?
我们安全部大部份同事私底下
Most of our colleagues in our bureau
每次提起民运
Mention about the democratic campaign
就有百分之九十以上的人
I say, 90% among us
就算不赞成也表示同情
Sympathize on them even if we don't agree
可是为了饭碗 职责所在
But for our work and duty
不得以才追捕他们的
We then run after and arrest them.
你呀 你小子刚才说话的语气
And you! Just then you said strangely
有点过份的激动做作
You are pretending and excited
我看你像在演戏一样
You're acting, I'll say
心里一定有鬼 给我铐起来！
You must have done something wrong, lock him up.
你那个兄弟说错了话
You man said something wrong
引起公安怀疑 被他们抓走了
And was arrested by the police
那怎么办？
Then?
你们要立刻出发
You must set out this minute
那个兄弟 等我以后想办法再救他
I'll try to rescue your man later
不行 我们六个人一起出来
No, we came here in 6
就要六个人一起回去
So we must leave in 6
我已经买通了海关
I've already bribed the Customs
如果去晚了 换了班就更麻烦啦！
It'll be troublesome if we arrive late and they change
王小慧 对不起
Sorry, Wang Siu Wai
希望你能够了解
I hope you can understand
我要对我兄弟有个交待
I must be responsible for my men
何必为了一个人牺牲那么多人呢？
Why sacrifice so many forjust one person?
去旅行也不会等了
No one will wait when we travel
何况是偷渡
And this is smuggling!
万大哥 如果我们尽量赶的话
Master Wan, if we rush all the way
可以有多少时间给我们呢？
How much time could we make out?
最多一个半小时
Ninety minutes the most.
万大哥 李先生 这样好不好
Master Wan, Mr. Li, what about this?
在这一个半钟头之内
Within this 90 minutes
我们尽量去救你的兄弟
We shall try our best to rescue your man
如果到时候还救不出来的话
If we fail even then
我们看情形再决定好吗？
We'll make the necessary decision
妈的 快说 说呀
Shit, say it quick, say.
说 快说
Say it quick.
他的脸拍好了没有？
Have you taken his picture?
拍好了！
It's done.
他妈的
Shit
说 快说！
Say, say it quick.
我操你屁股！
I do your ass!
大声点！
Louder.
我操你屁股！
I do your ass!
他妈的！快说 混蛋
Shit. Say, say it quick.
给我打
Beat him.
这个死不悔改的顽固份子
You lousy stubborn guy
拉到外面毙了算啦！
Take him out for execution!
是！
Yes.
阿火 阿火…
Fire...
阿火 你怎么样？
Fire... How are you?
把绳子解开！
Untie him first.
黄副局长 谢谢你的帮忙！
Sub-Chief, thanks for your help.
不用客气 我应该做的！
No thanks, I should do this.
停车！
Stop!
把通行证拿出来！
Show us your pass.
你们两个到上面看看！
You two get up and see
好…
Yes...
对不起 我想找洪队长
Sorry, where's Captain Hung?
找洪队长干吗？他下班了！
Captain Hung, he's off duty!
不是还有二十分钟吗？
He should be on duty for 20 minutes more?
-不知道 你到里面去看看吧  -好
- No idea, go there and find him. - Yes
洪队长…
Captain Hung...
妈的 你怎么现在才来呀？
Shit, why do you come only now?
真对不起 路上碰了点麻烦 所以才来晚了！
Sorry, there was trouble on the way So we arrive late.
对不起我也没办法
Sorry, I can't help you now
下一次你早一点
Come early nest time
我们合作这么久了 每一次都合作愉快
We've been in good term so far
老朋友了 麻烦你 帮帮忙嘛
Please do me a favour, old friend!
怎么帮啊？
How can I?
难道我把你的定金交给下一班不成
I can't take your money and give to people of next shift
这有三万块 麻烦你交给下一班
Here is $300000, take to the next shift
帮帮忙！我尽量呀
Please help me. I'll just try
不知道那家伙肯不肯买帐
But I don't know if he accepts or not.
孔队长呢？
Where's Captain Hong?
撒尿去了
In toilet.
等吧！
You can wait.
黄副局长 已经十点多啦
Sub-Chief Wang, it's 10 o'clock now
我看他不会来了
I think he won't come.
黄同志 等了很久了吧？
Comrade Wang, you've waited long?
什么话 等多久都无所谓
It's alright.
反正人参炖果子狸 炖得越久越好嘛！
The longer time the ginseng soup better anyway
你带走那个邮包货车司机 在哪里呀？
Where's the driver of the post you took away?
那个司机我已经查过了
I've checked that driver
没问题 我把他放了
Nothing wrong so I freed him.
这个是二十四军
This is 24th Army
一四一特种精锐部队第八旅的标志
141 group 8th division logo
这个人的真名叫黄正火
his real name is Wang Chin Fo
他是排长 八零年退伍
he was sergeant and retired in 1985
他退下来当司机也没有什么不对呀
it's nothing wrong to become driver after retirement
可是他八五年偷渡到香港 结伙抢劫
but he went to HK in 1985 and became robber
为什么会在这个时候在广州出现？
how come he is in Canton how?
还做替工司机？
How come he's substitute driver?
你打电话给邮政单位的那一个同志
Which comrade of the post office did you call
调查他身份的？
to check his identity?
不是我自己打的
I didn't make the call myself
你打给杜为东是不是？
You called up To Wai Tung, didn't you?
这个我也不清楚
I'm not sure
把杜为东带进来
Bring To Wai Tung in.
走 走呀
Go, go ahead.
你一向是跟着赵紫阳工作的
You've worked with Chiu Zee Yiang
你的司机举报你
Your chauffeur reported about you
说你在五月底跟六月初
Saying between May and June
不断的跟那些民运份子秘密接触
You kept contacting those pro-democrats
你在六月三号晚上 十一点四十七分
At 11:47 on 3 June
特地跑到白天鹅宾馆 化名李臣
You went to White Swan Hotel and used a name Li San
打国际电话去香港
And made a trunk call to HK
找声援会的欧阳卓 对不对？
To Au Yiang Chek of ASG, didn't you?
黄副局长 果子狸可以上了吗？
Sub-Chief Wang, can we serve now?
那我取消了？
Shall I cancel it?
你算什么东西？
Who are you to speak?
怎么能这么挥霍？
We must be thrifty now
上面有命令下来 要过八年的苦日子
There's order from senior that we must lead 8 years of hard life
这么浪费 找个暖壶 把它装起来
It's a waste, put it all in a hot opt.
是！
Yes.
XO也带走
Take the XO too.
老孔呀 我有个朋友做点小生意
Hong, my friend is doing a bit business
是一点点私货
He's smuggling a bit of stuff
是些药材 天麻什么的
Something like herbal medicine
希望您老人家给点面子 高抬贵手
I hope you will let him pass.
那部车呀？
Which car?
那边那辆车 正在搜的货柜
That one... the container being searched.
啥呀？
What is this?
钱呀！三千块
Money! Three thousand dollars
你在海关十几年
You've been in Customs for a decade
应该知道我的外号叫啥呀
You should have heard my nick name
叫啥呀？
What is it?
黑包公嘛！
Righteous Man!
知道就行了吧！
It's god you know.
老孔！
Hong!
把货都给我搬下来 快点
Take everything down, be quick.
挨着排的给我搜
Take it down and search carefully
你妈多大岁数啦？
How old is your mother?
上个月你是不是刚刚 给她做完九十大寿啊
Didn't you celebrate her 90th birthday last month?
你再不说出他们从那条路逃走的
If you don't say which route the took to escape
我就把你妈抓来
I'll have your mother arrested
一个也别落下
Don't miss any one
是
Yes
看啥呀 下去呀
Nothing to see, go down.
你咋受的伤呀
Why are you injured?
我被广州那些坏份子抢劫打伤的
I was robbed and injured by gangsters in Canton
看着他
Lay an eye on him
你妈的爸个小养子 啥药材啊天麻的乱七八糟胡雷啥
What damn shit medicine is this?
这是啥啊？
Medicine? You mean this?
老万 你妈的爸的小羔子
Wan, you damn bastard
你搞这里个笼来害我 你这个王八蛋
You harm me by doing this.
我操你妈 你居然是个人贩子
You bastard, you smuggle people? You smuggle people, bastard!
老孔 你打给谁呀
Hong, who are you calling?
这事大发了 我得向领导汇报
I must report to senior as this is a bit discovery
老孔 求你救救命
Hong, help me
大家兄弟一场
We are like brothers
你总不想看着老弟捱枪子儿吧？
You don't want to see me get shot, do you?
俺们一起做了十几年事
We've worked together for a decade
没有感情也有同情呀
I sympathize you I say
你这王八羔子 把我当啥呀
But y9u bastard, what do you take me as?
我是要小钱的呀？三千块打发我？
You take me as a beggar by giving me only $3000!
三千块？
$3000?
洪队长 我不是给您
Captain Hung, didn't I give you...
我操你妈 你是贩卖人口啊
Shut up, you smuggle people
少说也得拿出五万块来
You must at least pay us 50 thousand dollars
贩卖人口呀 五万块钱才几个子啊
Fifty thousand is good for smuggling people
可是民运份子 就是十万也不多
But one hundred thousand is not much for smuggling pro- democrats
绝对不是民运份子
Absolutely not pro-democrats
只不是几个乡姑娘想到香港去卖淫
They're country girls who want to be prostitute in HK
如今是非常时期
It's a very critical moment
就算不是我也当你是
I take they are even they are not!
叫老子去给她们验身呀
Or must I take them to verify?
得…我还是别贪这小便宜了
I'd better not take this bribe
等一等
Wait...
我这加上外币
With all the money I have
大概有八万多块 全都给您
There's about 80 thousand, I'll give it all to you
您帮帮忙 帮帮忙呀
Please do me a favour...
你们下车 把货搬回去吧
Get down and put the stuff back
大家伙帮忙把货搬回去
Help putting the stuff back now.
他妈抓来了
His mother is here.
带她进来
Take her in.
是
Yes.
等一等
Wait.
你说大声一点
Say louder.
你早点说就不用受苦啦
You could avoid this torture if you said earlier
我知道你是老干部 有五十年的党龄
I know you're experienced guy
一定会有很多人来救你的 是不是
So lots of people will rescue you
我不会放虎归山的
I won't ever let you off
黄临 根据中央的指示
Wang Lin, I have instruction from Central
快捕 快审 快决
Raped arrest, trial and execution
我判决你这叛徒死刑
I'm declaring death penalty to you
叫他妈来收尸
Ask his mother to collect his body.
是
Yes
是 是 我知道…
Yes... I know
袁同志 我知道
I know, Comrade Yuen
如果跑掉一个 你就拿你的头来见我
You must die if any of them runs away.
还有 尽可能抓活的！
And catch them alive.
是
Yes,
原来车上的人是头号通缉犯
People on the car are most wanted
如果抓了他们 他们会把我们供出来的
If we arrest them They will reveal that we're involved
一不做二不休 杀人灭口
So we can only, kill them
现在立刻封闭关口
Barricade the border now
任何人意图过边境 格杀勿论
Any who tries to get across will be killed
上呀 你他妈躲这儿干什么？
Go on, why are you hiding here?
上哪啊？你他妈的！
Shit you bastard, to ahead.
兵哥给你 上车！快
Master Bin, this is for you Get in the car, quick.
妈的
Shit...
袁同志 都走啦
Comrade Yuen, they're gone
立刻给我追
Chase them now.
下车
Get off the car.
从这里开始爬山
If we start climbing here
如果马不停蹄 一切顺利的话
Without pause and if everything is smooth
只要一天一夜
It takes 24 hours
爬过三个山头就能到达三里湾
And three hills to arrive a bay
那里有个渔村
There is a fishing village
到了那儿再想办法找渔船
We'll try to find a boat
一直开到对面就是香港范围了
It'll be HK side on the opposite
来
Come on.
快
Be quick.
我这里可以看到香港电视
I can watch HK TV from here
我认得这位姐姐
I recognize this sister
她是北高联的领袖
She's leader of the students
聪明
Smart!
你知不知道这里 有哪位叔叔是跑私货的？
Do you know any smuggler here?
知道
Yes!
谁呀？
Who?
我爸
My father.
他没有船怎么走私呀？
How can he smuggle without a boat?
有呀！他的快艇 像飞机一样快
Yes. He has a supper speedboat.
那么快呀？
Supper?
可不可以借我们跑一趟？
Can you lend it to us for a run?
行 没问题！
Sure, no problem.
你现在马上带我去看看快艇
Please take us to the boat now
是不是真的像你说的那么快？
We want to see if it's super as you said
好 现在去
Sure, we shall go now.
李先生 外面现在这种情况
Mr. Li, now the situation is so severe
对小孩子来说会不会太危险了
Will it be dangerous for the kid?
真是妇人之见 坏事
Lousy idea, this will make us suffer.
二零三
203!
对不起 我悔过
Sorry, I apologize.
姐姐 不用怕 我会潜水
Sister, don't panic, I can dive.
你有几个兄弟姐妹？
You have any brothers or sisters?
我妈只有我一个
I am the only child.
我想应该先征求他父母同意
I think we should first ask for his parent's consent
我明白你的意思
I know what you mean
可是我怕时间来不及呀
But we're running short of time
狗子 去吧！我不会反对的
Go ahead, I won't object the least.
这是我妈
This is my mother
谢谢你
Thank you
老头子
Old man.
什么事呀？
What is it?
不要出声
Don't make a noise.
往哪儿跑呀你
Where are you want to go?
什么人？出来
Who is it? Come out.
给我开枪
Start fire.
不要开枪 我是来捡海胆的
Don't fire, I come to fish.
在这里干什么？
Why are you here?
过来…
Come here.
走
Go.
在前面
They're ahead.
大兵哥 这边 快点
Master Bin, this way, be quick.
快点过去救他
Go and rescue him now.
快点 快过来！快点
Be quick, faster...
他妈的
Shit!
姐姐 我好冷呀
Sister, I'm very cold.
胖子 胖子
Fatty...
醒醒 醒醒啊 胖子
wake up... Fatty.
大嫂 这些钱是我们弟兄给你们的
This is the money we give you
你收下吧
Please take it.
为了救我们牺牲了这么多人
So many people sacrifice just for helping us
我这一辈子…都不会原谅我自己
For the rest of my wife... I won't forgive myself
你用不着内咎的
You needn't blame yourself
要革命 就一定要有牺牲
There must be sacrifice in revolution
当年打越战的时候
During the Vietnamese War
我也看着我多年的战友一个个倒下
I saw my colleagues dying one by one
可是当我想到只要国家有希望
But when I think of the hope of my country
我们这么做也是值得的
This is all worthwhile.
对不起
Sorry?
没关系
It's OK.
活生生的美人领袖投入你的怀里
A beautiful leader fell into you
这下你可逮着了
You run in good luck now!
大兵哥呀 刚才你说的正气凛然
Master Bin, you said just rightly
像模像样的 跟他妈真的似的
You said as if you meant it
不过呢 我觉得很肉麻
But for me, this is just lousy
说正经的 泡妞归泡妞
But wooing girls is wooing
在美丽的谎言之后呢
After these beautiful lies
还是快点把剩下来的钱 收回来的好啊
You'd better get all the balance of the money back
对不起 我悔过
Sorry, I apologize.
你是不是北京派来的？
Did the Peking Government sent you?
不是 我是本地人
No, I'm local people.
我是欧阳卓
Au Yiang Chek speaking.
欧阳校长 你到底做了些什么事？
Principal, what do you mean by this?
我们千辛万苦把小慧他们带出来
We tried hard to take them out here
你的手提电话我们怎么打都打不通
But your portable is no way to get through?
你是不是耍我们？
Are you fooling us?
兵哥 你不要误会
Master Bin, you mustn't misunderstand
因为邓小平露面之后
As soon as Tang Siao Pin showed up
形势就变了 人心也变了
People have changed their mind
我们这一趟的代价非常之大
We paid too much for this mission
跟我一起出生入死十几年的 胖子也被打死了
One of our men, Fatty, died too!
现在我最需要的就是钱
I need money badly now
你到底什么时候付钱接人呀？
When are you paying us and taking them away?
现在形势非常的紧张
It's very moment now
我出出进进都有人跟着我
I get followed day and night
手提电话也有人偷听
They even eavesdrop my portable phone
我根本找不到一个安全的地方
I can't find even a save place
来安置她们几个人
to settle them down
我求求你 再多给我一点时间
I beg you to give me a bit more time
不可能 多拖一天 就多一分危险
Impossible, the longer time the more danger will be
我以人格担保 多给我一个星期
I assure you, give me one more week
一人让一步 五天
Let's compromise, five days
我相信欧阳校长是一个讲信用的人
I believe we can trust Principal
这次的事情 一可以赚点钱
You can not only make money
二可以为中国人做点好事
But do something for Chinese people
做好事？
Do something?
十几年前 我们为国家去越南打仗
We went to Vietnamese War years ago...
那真是枪林弹雨 死里逃生
We all nearly got killed
结果又怎么样？
And the result?
还不是回乡下去种地
Going back home and become farmers!
现在又是枪林弹雨
We nearly got killed this time too
操他妈的 居然会被 香港的书呆子骗了
Shit, we were cheated by people of HK
有时候毛主席说得也他妈对
Sometimes Chairman Mao said just right
这知识份子就是臭老九 靠不住
Educated people are evil and unreliable
还有呢
Moreover...
咱们哥几个呢 可只收了他十五万订金
We've only takedn$150000 as deposit
连我们以前抢回来的钱 可全都送给胖子他老婆了
But we gave it to fatty's wife with the money we robbed
我可实话实说
Frankly saying
爱不爱国不关我的事
Patriotism is nothing concerned with me
我他妈的只知道爱钱
I only care for money
谁管他是什么…校长
I don't care what Principal he is
用他妈什么…借口
Or whatever excuse he has
反正欠我的钱就不行
I just won't let anyone owe me money!
谁理他是什么声援会
Whatever Aiding Group he belongs
又什么互助会的
Or whatever damn thing that is
不给钱就把他打成大头会
I will surely teach him something.
说得对
Right
大兵哥 有困难呀？
Master Bin, is there trouble?
没有 我们兄弟之间的私事
No, it's only our own affairs.
联络上欧阳校长了没有？
Have you contacted Principal?
刚刚通过电话 他还叫我问候你
I just talked to him on the phone
你就放心好了
Don't worry a bit!
他已经安排好让你们离开香港
He's arranged for you to leave HK
只是正在研究让你们坐船走呢
He's thinking whether you should take a ship
还是搭飞机
or by plane.
这些标语是游行用的啊？
Is this for the demonstration?
是呀 是我跟兄弟们参加游行用的
Yes, they are for it.
我们还喊口号呢
We even shout slogans
这些字呢？谁写的？
But who wrote it?
怎么啦？
Why?
写的好漂亮
They are pretty.
我随便乱涂乱画的 谢谢
I just wrote them casually, thanks.
你看看 这是俺写的 怎么样
Look, I wrote this, how do you think?
字如其人 很有力
Just like you, very strong
从字里行间就可以看得出来
I can tell by the way they're written
你的爱国程度已经达到了热情奔放
You are indeed very patriotic!
真的？
Really?
哥 她说啥呀
Brother, what did she say?
字如其人啊 小弟！
The words like him, brother.
陈同志 追捕民运份子
Comrade Chen, in order to arrest pro-democrats
政治保卫局 决定派袁树同志负责
Political Defense Bureau is sending Comrade Yuen for
袁将于明天去香港
He's going to HK tomorrow
必须全力协助 京九号
You must assist him.
袁主任 非常欢迎您
Chief Yuen, welcome
由您领导真是太好了
It's too good with you as leader
那里
It's nothing...
开车 快
Go, hurry
王Sir电话
Officer Wang, your call
喂
Hello!
好的
Sure
打电话给交通总部
Call Traffic Department
叫他们立刻去找一部 蓝色的万事发小型货车
Ask them to look for a blue Mazda van
车牌好像是BE1389 找到了先跟踪他们
The plate number is BE1389 Just follow it if they find it
千万不要打草惊蛇
And don't alert them.
是
Yes, sit.
阿斌 立刻找飞虎队
Bun, call Swat now.
是
Yes, sir.
努力的想想 你一定会想到的
Just think hard and you will recall
不要啊…
No...
我求求你
Please...
孩子哭得你伤心了吧
You're hurt by your son's crying, right?
臭小子！不许哭 不许哭 臭小子
Bastard, don't cry...
不要 我想…我努力的想
No...
你轻一点呀 娃儿好像被掐死了
Wake up, is my son killed?
儿子！
No...
胡说八道 吓晕了嘛
Shit, he's only fainted.
妈的 你个老乌龟
Shit, you old bastard!
一天拖一天 今天要是收不到钱
You drag day by day, if I don't get money today
我一枪打烂你的头
I must blow up your head.
喂 欧阳太太 你就是呀？
Hello, Mrs. Au Yiang? You are?
你现在给我老老实实听清楚
You must listen to me carefully
你老公欠我六十五万
You husband owes me $650000
我现在正在招待他呢
So I'm teaching him something
你马上拿钱来赎他回去
You must take money at once if you want him back
你说什么？没钱？
What? No money?
你别他妈装蒜了
You mustn't pretend you are poor
没个几千万的家当
If you don't have millions of dollars
当他妈那门子声援会的主席啊？
How can he be chairman of ASG?
你等等！跟你老婆交待后事吧
Wait! You may tell your wife your will!
兵哥 我们说好限期五天
Master Bin, we fixed a period of 5 days
今天已经是第七天了
And it's the seventh day now
以前我们一向听你的指挥
We used to take you as our leader
这一次我想应该由我来作主
But I want to make a decision this time
因为大伙推荐我出来
As they selected me out
也是为了大家的前途着想
Just for the good future of ours!
兵哥 我是因为没安排好船
Master Bin, as I haven't arranged for the ship
所以才拖延了几天
So I delayed paying you two days
我不是故意不给你们钱的
I didn't mean to do this
校长的出发点也是为了爱国
Principal means good anyway
现在出现了问题
Now that problems arouse
为什么不能多给他几天时间呢？
Why don't we give him a few days more?
你没经过我的同意
Without my consent you people made your own decision
擅自采取行动
And even take action
把我当什么啦？
What do you think I am?
你们几个还把我当你们大哥吗？
Do you still take me as your boss?
四肢发达头脑简单你们
Why are you so simple-minded?
不能解开
You mustn't untie him
你如果解开他
If you should until him
我们兄弟关系到此为止
Our relation breaks up!
我知道你心里在想什么
I know what you are thinking
你他妈也得看看实际情况呀
But you should still look into the situation
假爱国 我都想吐了我
You pretend patriotic, you make me sick.
你自己才公私不分呢
You are doing this to your own interest
你不过是因为喜欢小慧才这样做的
As you love Siu Wai
可是再怎么说 你也不应该拿我们玩命的血汗钱
You shouldn't take the hard money we made
去做人情啊？
to do favour for your love!
泡什么大学生嘛
You want to woo university student?
你当你自己是什么东西呀
What do you think you are?
有钱的大少爷？
You think you are master?
说句不好听的 你不过是个强盗
To say frankly you are a bandit!
做什么春秋大梦？
You are day-dreaming, you know?
你还是等分了钱之后
You'd better divide our money
自己去大富豪找个正点的 玩玩更他妈实际
And get a better one in Volvo Club!
有没有学问 上了床都一个德性
Girls are the same when they're on bed.
我跟了你十八年
I've been with you 18 years
一起打仗 一起抢劫 出生入死
W used to fight, rob together
没想到你会为了一个女人打我？
But you beat me for a woman!
你不配当我大哥！
You're not up to be my boss.
哥 你说呢？
Brother, shat do you say?
说啥？你吃大便长大的
What to say? Can you think yourself?
啥都问俺
Why must you ask me?
当我第一次看到你们的时候
When I first met you people
我对你们几个产生一种无比的敬意
I was so respectful to you
在自由世界生活的香港人
As people living in the free HK
居然可以舍生忘死
Could went through all trouble
把我们从白色的恐怖中救出来
To save us from White Terror!
我觉得我们的血并没有白流
I felt we did so right even when we're injured
我死去的同胞也可以安息了
And the people who died may rest in peace
可是没想到你们是打家劫舍的强盗
But I can't imagine you are robbers and bandits
见利忘义的流氓
People who do anything for money
你们又何必这样虐待校长呢？
Why must you do this torture to Principal?
不就是要钱吗你们？
You just want money?
我相信我在中共的眼里面 还值一点钱
I'm sure I am worth something for Chinese Government
既然你这么爱钱的话 把我交给中共
Since you like money, take me to Chinese Government
去拿你们应得的酬劳啊
And get the reward, shy don't you?
抓我吧！抓我呀
Just tie me up...
为什么不敢抓我？
Why don't you tie me up?
好 如果你不抓我的话
Ok, if you don't tie me up
我就带欧阳校长走
I'll take Principal away.
不能解开
You mustn't untie him.
你想干什么？
What do you want?
除非你答应不走
Unless you promise not to run away
为什么？
Why?
就凭这几个书呆子
Just about these people
他们自身都难保了
They can't protect themselves
怎么去保护你们？
How can they protect you students?
我也不可能跟你们这些 人面兽心的人在一起啊
I will absolutely not stay with bandits like you!
把他们也绑起来
Tie them up too.
你到底想干什么？想绑架啊？
What do you want? You want to kidnap us?
随便你怎么想 我就绑架
As you like, just take it as kidnap if you want
不错 我们还有钱没收齐呢
Right, we haven't received our money
我们是强盗 这样行了吧
And we are bandits, right?
喂
Hello!
大兵哥 我对不起你
Master Bin, I am so sorry...
大嫂 发生什么事了？
What has happened?
那些特务抓了我们母子
Some agents came to me
我对不起你 我把你们出卖了
I'm so sorry to have betrayed you
大嫂 你现在在哪里？
Where are you now?
在你家外面
Outside your place
王兵 我是政治保卫局的袁树
Wang Bin, I'm Yuen Su of Political Defence Bureau
我现在命令你把三个通缉犯
I order you to hand out the three wanted convicts
王小慧 洪韵音 陈英 立刻交出来
Wang Siu Wae, Hung Yuen Yin, Chen Yin
我以国家的信誉保证
I assure you with the honor of the country
放你一条生路
To let you go off!
否则五分钟之后 我们就攻进来
Otherwise we'll rush in 5 minutes
把你们全部消灭
And terminate you all!
狗公 现在谁是大哥？
Doggy, who's the boss now?
在这种危险情形之下 当然你做大哥啦
Of course you are in such situation
兵哥 你就是大哥
Brother Bin, you're the boss.
各就各位 拿家伙
Get ready for your weapons.
好 快
Sure, be quick.
大石小石 保护校长和女同学
Brothers Stone, protect Principal and the Students
你把手枪分给他们自卫
Give them guns for self-defense
好
Good!
拿着
Take it.
校长 各位女同学 你们看到啦？
Principal, students, you see now
我们也是讲义气的
We are righteous in basic
阿火 都什么时候了还那么多废话
Fire, why are you murmuring in this minute?
-准备作战！  -是！
- Ready for fight! - Yes.
校长 我能活着回来再继续说
Principal, I'll talk again if I survive
校长 你用不着担心
Principal, don't worry.
快点 快
Be quick...
这边 快
This way, fast.
袁同志 你要来真的啊？
Comrade Yuen, you mean it?
搞出人命 我可负不了这个责任
I can't take responsible if anything happens
妈的 你想不想升官啊？
Shit, don't you want promotion?
越乱升的机会越大
You'll get promotion if there's chaos
抓到机会就要拼嘛
So make use of this opportunity.
我看先跟上头请示一下怎么样
I'd better report to the seniors.
妈的！香港这么小 人口这么多
Shit, HK is over-populated
死了几个有什么关系？
It's nothing just some of them die!
他们的位置在这里
They are here.
行动！是！快！
Action, Yes, sir.
快
Hurry
妈的 派一队人到后面支援
Shit, send someone to the back
是
Yes, sir.
那些大圈那里找来这么多人
Why are so many Chinese gangsters?
简直像打仗一样
It's a war indeed.
立刻叫飞虎队到前面包围
Send SWAT to the front.
是
Yes, sir.
还有 叫飞虎队多派点人来
And send some more SWAT here
-叫陆海空三军准备  -是
- Armies, Air Force must stand by too - Yes, sir
其他人向目标进攻
Others proceed to the target
那些民运份子呢都跑哪儿去了？
Where are all the pro-democrats?
报告 下面有地道
Report, there's tunnel.
给我搜
Search!
报告 发现有隧道
Report, a tunnel is found
带我去！
Take me there
是
Yes.
他妈的 给我下去
Shit, get down.
是
Yes.
妈的 搜
Shit, get down
是
Yes.
上车 来
Get in the car come on
陈同志 我们到底是跟谁在打啊？
Comrade Chen, who is our opponent?
我好像看到的是飞虎队
I think they are SWAT
香港皇家警察
People of Royal HK Police Force
我们怎么跟香港的公安人员 打起来了呢？
How come we are fighting with HK Policemen?
这…这个我需要去调查调查
I must... I must investigate.
调查…调你妈个头啊
Shit, investigate?
拍什么？还拍？
Why are you still taking pictures?
袁同志 我们快要全军覆没了
Comrade Yuen, our people are nearly all injured
投降吧 由你去谈判
We shall surrender, you'll negotiate
记住要保持尊严
Remember to remain respectable
不能对英方让步 要强硬 强硬 强硬
You mustn't compromise to the British, be hard...
停火
Hold your fire.
谁是你们的最高负责人啊？
Who is in charge in here?
叫他出来见我
Ask him to see me.
你们想干什么？
What do you want?
我们准备动手术帮他把子弹拿出来
We're going to get the bullet out.
难道你们是外科医生吗？
Are you surgeons?
不是 不过打仗的时候
No, but during the wars
我看过军医怎么救人
I saw surgeons do it.
那不是拿他的生命开玩笑
You're joking with his life!
不行 马上送他去医院
No, you must take him to hospital at once.
香港的医院是要看身份证的
But hospitals here request ID card
我们是通缉犯
And we are 3wanted convicts
不是等于送他去坐牢吗？
We're in fact sending him to jail
也比被你们这样活生生整死好
But it's still better to be killed by you.
如果这样就会暴露我们的行踪
If our location is revealed
所有的人都会有危险
We will all be in danger
我们总不能够为了自己的安全
But we can't just care about our safety
而牺牲他的生命呀
And let him die like that
你闭嘴 都是你这个小狐狸精害的
Shut up! This happens because of you
一到香港就该把你们干掉
We should have deserted you once we came back to HK
是大兵哥不准咱们这么做的
But brother Bin stopped us doing that.
你胡说些什么啊？
Don't bullshit!
大兵 你现在被女鬼迷住啦
Bin, you're being selected now.
在你的英勇领导之下
Under you command
胖子已经回老家了
Fatty died already
现在阿火呢 眼看着也快要断气了
And Fire is dying at this moment
我知道 我知道你现在想什么
I know, I know what you want
最好我们这些兄弟都死光了
We'd better all die
那些钱就全部归你了
And you'll get all the money
然后你就跟这个小狐狸精去美国
And you'll go to US with this woman
双宿双栖 对不对？
And spend the rest of your life there
哥 你说呢？
Brother, what do you say?
我说…阿火说得对 俺也这么想
I say... Fire is right. I think so too.
你都听到了吧
So you hear?
我跟大石小石打算分了钱之后
Stone Brothers and I have decided after we get the money
我们就各走各的
We shall split up.
我快断气了 你们还吵个什么劲呀
I'm nearly dying and you deep arguing?
我念医科的 也许帮得上忙
I'm a medical student, maybe I can help.
好吧
OK.
这位是李副杜长
This is Sub-Chief Li
真正的身份是港澳地区 地下党委书记
He's real title is Underground Secretary of HK region
这位是袁树同志
This is Comrade Yuen
他是政治保卫局的特派员
He's agent of Political Defence Bureau
他妈的 陈兴 你还记得我是党委书记吗？
Chen Shin, you still remember I'm Secretary?
你们政治保卫局 太目中无人了
You people from PDB are too proud
我们组织的纪律是 一切要归党委领导
Rule by Party Secretary is our tradition
你到香港来 没有人知会我呀
But no one informed me you'd come to HK
好啦！阁下现在闯祸啦
Ok, now that you've made a mess
就连你大便往我头上扣
And make me stand up to it!
你妈妈的不开花
You damn shit!
李同志 我们绝对没有 不尊重你的意思
Comrade Li, we do respect you
你尊重我个屁啊！
Respect me shit!
几个月了 你也不向我汇报你的工作情况
You haven't reported your duty for months
就会在我背后搞什么阴谋诡计
You know only make plots behind me.
李同志 责任我们以后再说
Comrade Li, let's talk about that later
现在先解决目前的问题
We must solve the present problems
你还好意思讲
Dare you say?
谁批准你在这里大开杀戒的
Who let you do all the killing here?
现在是一塌糊涂 双方共有八死三十六伤
Eight people died and 36 casualties!
这个消息要是传了出去
If this news is revealed
会严重破坏香港的安定繁荣
It'll spoil the stability of HK
你叫我怎么干下去呀？
How can I work on?
我要在总书记面前告你这王八蛋
I must report this to the Chief Secretary
李同志 你说话客气一点啊
Comrade Li, care about what you say
这次我这样做
The reason I do all this
完全是因为你在这里的工作 搞得一塌糊涂
Is because you made a mess work in here
好啦 舆论基地被人家抢走了
Now our newspapers are taken away
中资机构的员工上街游行
Our employees went to demonstrate!
你这个党委书记是怎么当的？
What kind of Secretary are you?
我怎么知道你身边会有多少 同情民运的份子
How can I know if there're pro-democrats around you?
要我知会你？
Why must I inform you?
泄露了秘密谁负责？
Who'll take responsibility if secrets are revealed?
袁同志 你怎么可以这样说话？
Comrade Yuen, how can you say such things?
还有你呀！
And you!
你一直都敷衍我 你没有全力协助我工作
You've been working vaguely and never helped me up
我怀疑你是资产阶级自由化份子
I suspect you're our betrayer!
你来香港才五年
You've been in HK for 5 years
你的思想彻底腐化了
You've changed your view
还有呀！你在外国银行存了很多外币
And you have much savings abroad!
-你冤枉我！  -我没冤枉你
- You're framing me. - I'm not.
-我哪冤枉你了？  -你为什么冤枉我？
- You bastard. - Why must you frame me?
你他妈的
You're Fascist...
李副社长 十五分钟时间到了
Sub-Chief Li, 15 minutes is up
好
Ok...
好 现在我要去向英方交涉
I'm to negotiate with the British
我们党的政策呢
And our usual policy
一向是不管内部有多大的矛盾
Whatever internal clash there is
我们对外一定要团结怎么样
We must unite to resist, how's that?
-对！  -来！
- Right. - Come on.
枪口对外！对！
Resist together.
枪口对外
Right.
Unite to resist!
走
Go.
大卫 我们的人伤亡情况如何？
How are our people?
三个人死亡 三个垂危
Three dead, three in critical conditions
两个脱离危险期
Two have gone through
三个情况欠佳
Three in severe condition
其余七个要留医
And seven in hospital.
你妈的大陆人想干什么？
Shit you Chinese people, what do you want?
我可以控告你们这些大陆人谋杀
I can charge you of murder
全关进牢里
And lock you all in jail.
九七以前香港还是归 我们英国人管的
We're still to rule before 1997
你们太无法无天了
You're too lousy and daring.
这样做是破坏了中英联合声明
You're spoilt the joint Declaration
港督跟首相全傻了
HK Governor and the Prime Minister must be crazy
你们这群家伙简直是野蛮人
You're really barbarians!
妈的 大陆人
Shit! Chinese people!
陈同志 你对他讲
Comrade Chen, talk to him.
李同志 你说话比较有力
Comrade Li, you're sharp tongue
还是由你来发言
So you'd better talk.
操你妈的
Shit!
要不是你们纵容香港声援会那群人
Shit! If you hadn't let the ASG off
把香港弄成这个…反革命基地
And turned HK into a base of anti-revolution
就不会出现现在这种情况了
This would not have happened
还有呀 你们不尊重中国的立场
And moreover, you don't respect the Chinese Government
干涉中国的内政
You're interfering with China internal affair
我警告你 所有的后果 要由你们几个人负责
I warn you, you must take full responsibility of this
我告诉你 中国人不是好欺负的
I'll tell you, you can't tease Chinese people
不像你们这些英国人白皮猪
We're not like you, English pigs
搞阴谋 搞小动作
You make all plots and dirty tricks
你们是坏份子 伪君子 帝国主义者
You're bandits, hypocrites, nationalists!
你们是猪 是纸老虎
You're pig, paper tiger.
是猪 是纸老虎
Pig, paper tiger.
还有什么补充呢？
Anything to add?
还有什么补充的？
有 英国完蛋去
Yes; Fuck off Britain.
你们这些屠杀平民的刽子手
You slaughter, murderer who killed people
懦夫 法西斯
You coward, Fascists.
喂 港督先生
You Excellency.
是的
Yes...
最高层决定为了避免进一步打击
The seniors have decided: In order not to strike up
香港人的信心和社会安定繁荣
The confidence of HK people
决定要掩饰这件事
This matter is to be kept secret
至于被捕的中方特务 包括你在内
And for the agents arrested
马上驱逐出境
Are to be expelled at once, including you!
我跟我的三个手下
My three men and I
是外交部派驻尼加拉瓜的外交人员
Are diplomat in Nigrara
有外交豁免权
We have diplomat exemption
你们不可以这样对我们
You can't do this to us.
我们三个人在一个月之内 会自动离境
We'll leave HK within one month
我要你保证在香港这段时间内 不会再闹事
You must assure you won't make a mess anymore.
我以国家的信誉保证
I assure you with the honour of my country
你们国家还有信誉吗？
Your country still has honour?
抗议
Object!
你这样说是侮辱我的国家 抗议
You're insulting our country, object.
抗议
Object!
你们不要再吵了
Stop shouting!
现在最重要的是向外界交待
It's most important to tell the press
这个漏子捅得太大了
But this is a serious case
新闻记者追得很紧哪
The pressmen will run hard for it.
我们可以说是大圈帮自相残杀
We'll tell them it's a fight between Chinese gangsters
被警方围劝剿才爆发血战
And a gun battle followed as police arrived!
我也是这么想
I do think the same.
这个就叫做英雄所见全同 是吗？
So heroes think alike, right?
你笑什么？
What are you laughing at?
谁对你们笑啦？
Who is laughing to you?
什么东西好笑
What's so funny?
开车
Start the car.
计程车
Taxi!
老陈 通知澳门的同志准备出发
Chen, inform people of Macau to set out any time
袁同志 你…
Yuen, you...
这是命令
This is an order!
好 对 坐马拿马船去美国
Right, take a ship to US
后天早上七点正
7 o'clock a.m. The day after tomorrow
青山湾码头会合
we shall meet at Castle Peak Pier
坐游艇出海
we'll take a tug out
船长我已经说好了
I've talked with the Captain
钱我也准备好了 你相信我就是了
I've prepared the money too, just believe me.
黄总警司 你笑什么？
Superintendent Wang, what're you laughing?
大家心里有数
We all know.
我是奉了上头的命令
I am sent to tell you something
来传达点讯息给你
Some news to you!
我听着了 你说吧
I'm listening, go ahead.
站在政府的立场 这件事一定不能够公开
On the side of Government this can't be revealed
我们会睁只眼闭只眼
So we will take laissez-faire
不去拘捕这一群非法入境的学生
And ever arrest these students
因为如果抓了他们 那他们是一定活不成的
As they'll surely die if we arrest them
交给大陆舆论会攻击我们的
But if we hand them back to China, public opinion will attack us
如果不交给大陆 政治庇护他们
If we protect them and not hand them back
中港关系会非常的紧张
Relation between HK and China will turn bad
所以我希望你能够尽快把他们送走
So I hope you will send them away as soon as possible
我明白 我会尽快办的
I know, I'll do that fast.
校长 这件事我帮了你很大的忙
Principal, since I've done you a favour
别忘了你欠我一个人情
You must help me back
这帮大圈仔 我早就想抓他们了
I've always wanted to arrest those Chinese Gansters
你要把他们交出来
So you must hand them to me.
叫我出卖他们？办不到
You want me to betray them? Never!
中国人是不会出卖朋友
Chinese will never betray others.
我只有事后抓你了
Then I must arrest you afterwards
我会告你知情不报 包庇通缉犯
I'll charge you of covering up wanted convicts
你不要忘了 很多人都希望你死
Don't forget, many people want you die.
谢谢你又救了我们一次
Thanks for saving us once more
真对不起 那天我说错了话误会了你
Sorry, I misunderstood you the other day.
我现在郑重的跟你道歉
I must apologize to you now.
你仍然把我当你的朋友 我觉得很光荣
I feel fine as you still take me as friend
都是你的战友呀
They're all your people.
跟我一起出来的兄弟
The people who came to HK with me
死的死 失踪的失踪
Have died and disappeared
剩下来的都成了通缉犯啦
The rest all become wanted convicts
谢谢你们为了我们的事
I must thank you, for our affairs
要让你们兄弟不和 真不好意思
That you and your men have dispute!
这个你不用担心
Don't care about that
其实狗公这个人 直肠子一个
Doggy is indeed very straight
说完就没事
He doesn't mean what he says
真的
Really?
他傻不拉叽的 狗嘴里吐不出象牙
He's stupid and don't care about his words
他居然会说我对你有意思
He said I loved you!
真笑死人了 其实我怎么会有那么笨呢
So funny, how will I be so stupid?
我早就知道你已经有男朋友了
I know long ago you have a boyfriend
你怎么知道的
Where did you learn this?
是你同学陈英说的
Your schoolmates Chen Yin told me
她说你们六四那天晚上
She said on the night of June 4th
不知怎么的分散了
You and him got separated.
对了 你们是不是真的分散了
Right, are you really separated up?
就在六月三日晚上十点半
At 10:30 on night of June 4th
木樨地那边传出了枪声
There were shots in MuXi area
他跟我说 今天晚上会死很多人
He told me many would be killed
我们身为民运领袖的
And being student leaders
一定要有人带头牺牲 才对得起那些死难同胞
Someone must take the lead to sacrifice
才可以激发人民的义愤
And to muster up courage of people
他说这件事容易做 让他去做
He said this was easy and he would do it
可是同时一定要有人生存下去
But meanwhile someone must survive
才可以继续为民运奋斗
To go on struggling for democracy
这件事难做 让我去做
He let me do it as this is very difficult
他说完之后就一个人 带头往西长安街
Then he took some students to Chian An Street West
去拦截那些坦克车
To block those tanks
一个钟头以后 那些人把他抬回来
One hour later, his body was brought back
尸体上…尸体上有四十七个子弹孔
On his body... there were 47 bullet holes
真是了不起
Great,
不像我们只知道爱钱
but we only care for money
你说什么？
What did you say?
我没说什么
Nothing
我只是说你以后的日子 一定会很艰苦
I said you'd lead all hard life in future
真了不起
Great man,
真是太了不起了
really great!
喂 谁呀？
Hello, who's it?
他准备偷渡到哪里？
Where're they going?
那船叫什么名字？
The name of the ship?
不错 我认为首先应该通知中方
Right, I think we should inform Chinese Government
这是一个改善中港关系的好机会
This is a good chance to improve our relation
出了公海就不关我们的事
It's nothing to do with us in the high seas
我们也用不着承受舆论的压力
We won't face pressure of the press too
领导给我的指示 格杀勿论
I have instructing, kill them!
明白了吗？
Do you understand?
谢谢袁主任给我们的训示
Thanks for instructing us, comrade Yuen.
我们一定遵守 格杀勿论
We will obey, kill them!
格杀勿论
Kill them!
快
Faster.
快点
Faster...
到船舱
Get to the cabin.
阿火
Fire!
这里是六十七万
This is $670000
多出来的两万是我自己拿出来的
I tock the extra $20000 out myself
就算是尽我一点心意 给那位兄弟的抚恤金
For the family the Fatty.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的助手 他认识那个船长
My helper knows the Captain
待会儿 他会陪你们一起出发
He will go with you later
还有啊 等你们回来的时候
And when you come back
千万不能在这里上岸
Remember not to come back here
因为我知道警方查你们查得很紧
As I know police are looking madly for you
记住了 保重
Remember, take care.
再见
Goodbye.
你的行为 我会原谅你的
I'll forgive what you've done
狗哥 保重
Master Doggy, take care.
谢谢
Thank you.
保重
Take care.
保重！
好好照顾自己
Take care of yourself.
麻烦大了校长
Principal, it's really bad.
原来四眼七是个内奸呀
Chi is the betrayer.
四眼七
Chi?
是！四眼七？
Yes Chi?
证据呢？
Is there evidence?
她就是四眼七的女朋友
She's girlfriend of Chi
她无意中听到四眼七 打电话给那个警司
She overheard Chi talking on the phone with that Superintendent
你到底什么时候知道他是个线民的
When did you learn that he's betrayer?
昨天晚上偷听到的
I overhead it only last night.
我心里也很矛盾
I feel very contradict
阿七他说…他要跟我结婚的
Chi said he'd marry me soon
你为什么不立刻打电话给我？
Why didn't you call me up at once?
你的手提电话没有打开呀
You turned off your portable phone.
糟了 为什么那个警司
It's bad, and that Superintendent
要知道这些偷渡的细节呢？
Why did he want the details of their trip?
为什么？为什么？
Why?
难道他想通知中方
He wants to inform Chinese Government?
完了 那个货船不就是 一个死亡的陷阱
Finished! That ship is a dead trap for them.
天呀 天呀 欧阳卓 镇定一点
Jesus, I...
欧阳卓 你要镇定一点
Au Yiang Chek, take it easy...
天呀 我镇定不下来啊
I can't keep calm...
你不要哭了 哭得我烦死了
Don't cry, you make me nervous.
不用怕！怎么样？
Don't panic. What then?
那船还没到嘛
That tug hasn't come yet.
船已经开了 人也走啦
It went away already.
没关系 船上有电话
It's Ok, there's mobile phone on it.
幸亏我镇定 临危不乱
I am so calm to think of that
我来听
I'll answer.
喂
Hello
喂 校长？我是阿七呀 有什么事吗
Hello, Principal? Chi speaking, what's it?
没有 你们顺利吗？
Nothing, is everything going fine?
还顺利
Yes, it is.
叫小慧来听电话 我想托她买点东西
Ask Siu Wai, please, I want her to buy me something
她上洗手间了
She's in toilet.
那叫王兵来
Then ask Bin please.
好的 你等一会儿
Ok, please hold on.
喂 喂
Hello!
糟了 这怎么办？
It's bad, what shall we do?
镇定点 镇定点
Take it easy...
他们的手提电话呢？试试看嘛
What about their portable phone? Let's try
对啦
Right!
这不是见阎王了吗？我操他妈的
They're in danger, shit!
我怎么讲脏话了？
Why? I spelt?
校长 你千万不要告诉阿七
Principal, you must never tell Chi
是我跟你说的
That I told you this
小姐呀 你不要哭好不好
Miss, will you stop crying?
我正在想办法呀 我拜托你别哭
I'm thinking of a way, please don't cry.
怎么 想打我呀？
How's it you want to beat me?
校长 我早跟你说过
Principal, I've told you before
我不会放过那些大圈帮的
That I'll never let those gangsters off.
这个我不怪你
I don't blame you for that
我只怪你为什么出卖 那些学生领袖
I just blame you of betraying those students!
你已经知道了 那最好不过了
So you know that already?
跟我没有关系 这个是上头的意思
It's nothing to do with me, the seniors decided it
北京威协说要断水断副食品
The Chinese Government threatened to cut off water food supply to HK
上头为了大局着想
To safe guard HK
所以就让那些大陆人到公海去抓人
So we let the Chinese agents to arrest them in high seas
既可以做个顺水人情
We can then improve our relation
我们又不用负责任
And we don't have to take responsible
去你妈的
Shit!
你知不知道他们被抓回去 会被枪毙的
Do you know they'll be shot when they're arrested?
你这样做等如是凶手 刽子手
You're slaughter and murderer as you did that.
我知道 不过你说这三条人命要紧
I know, but these three students are more important
还是香港六百万人的 安定繁荣要紧呢
Or the stability of HK is more important?
如果中港关系破裂了
If relation between China and HK breaks off
香港就会变成死港
HK will surely die
六百万人就得投奔怒海
And all 6 million people must flee
我们的立场是要对香港市民负责任
And our duty is to safeguard HK
校长…
Principal...
叫救护车 送他去医院
Call for ambulance, send him to hospital.
是
Yes. Sir.
校长
Principal.
拜托你了船长
Captain, I beg you
麻烦你照顾她们
to take good care of them.
好的 你放心 我会好好照顾她们
Don't worry, I'll take good care of them.
谢谢你 再见
Thanks goodbye.
大兵哥 保重
Master Bin, take care.
妈的 讲…怎么这么噜苏
Shit... what are they murmuring about?
要是再讲 把他们给我拉出去毙了他
Shoot them up if they talk on.
那些家伙身上有枪
They're carrying guns
为了同志们安全着想
For the sake of our people
无谓的伤亡 是可免则免
So try to avoid unnecessary casualties
难道你是这里的总指挥啊？
Are you commander?
不是呀
No.
闭上嘴
Then shut up.
五分钟之后如果他们再不走 立刻行动
If they don't leave in 5 minutes, we'll take action
是 主任
Yes, Chief Yuen
大兵 不要妨碍人家开船啦
Bin, don't stop them sail off.
还有什么话 留着等写信再说吧
You might write to each other if you must.
我们回去啦
We must go back now.
小慧 你好好保重
Siu Wai, take care.
拜拜
Bye.
大兵 送君千里 终需一别 走吧
Bin, we must leave, so go away.
过来
Come on
大兵船上有解放军
Bin, there're Liberation Army on board
刚才你在船上为什么 不早一点暗示我呢？
Why didn't you imply to me on board?
我怎么暗示你啊
How could I?
我估计船上最少有 一百多支枪对着我们
I guess there were over hundred guns pointing at us
我们一动手就会变蜜蜂窝
We'd be shot over if we moved.
四眼七 叫游艇全速掉头 去追那艘货船
Chi, ask the tug to turn back to the ship
大家准备家伙 全面备战
Get ready for a battle
大兵 回去一定完蛋 根本就无战可备
Bin, there's no battle, we'll all die if we go back
你不要再为了这一个女人
You mustn't do all that for the woman
要我们大家陪你去送死 好不好
And make us die for her too
大兵 你清醒一点 别再糊涂下去了
Bin, wake up and don't fool around.
哥 你说呢？
Brother, what do you say?
我说…我说也没什么好说的了
I say... I have nothing to say.
兵哥 是不是应该冷静一点 把钱先分了
Brother Bin, should we be calm and divide the money?
阿火 你说呢
Fire, what do you say?
以卵击石是不智的行为
Though this is a real risk for us
不是所谓拿人钱财 替人消灾
But we got paid to do that
如果这一次不去 就是不够义气
If we don't go, we're evil
因为这次的事情不是一般性的
As this is no normal case
你别那么多废话 你用最简单 最直接的方法告诉我
Don't bullshit, just answer me directly
-去还是不去？  -不去
- Yes or no? - No!
大兵哥 不行呀 船长不肯调头呀
Master Bin, the captain refused to turn back
哥 你说呢？
Brother, what do you say?
我说…我想到了
I say... I think of it now
兵哥这一次的做法 其实不是为了个女人
Brother Bin does this not for the woman
他是为了民运
He does it for democracy
我们要讲一点义气
We must be righteous
死 有轻于鸡毛 有重于大山
Dying counts on worthy or not
我们兄弟俩是大山
We will die if it is worthwhile
俺也这么想
I think that too.
狗公 你说呢
Doggy, what do you say?
我说
I say...
我说狗公 死就死 还说个屁
I say, doggy, just die but don't say.
开枪
Open fire.
快 快点走
Faster, run fast.
快点 走
Run fast.
快点
哥…
Brother.
哥 你说呢？
Brother, what do you say?
我说
I...
我…
我说不出来了以后你要自己说
I can say no more, you must say yourself from now on
哥…
Brother.
小石
Be careful.
立刻去枪毙那三个反革命份子 绝对不可以让他们逃跑
Shoot those 3 anti-revolutionists, don't let them run off!
为什么不杀他们 为什么？
Why don't you kill them? Why?
我…我下不了手啊
I can't do that.
你他妈的
You bastard.
过来
Come over.
别开枪 不然的话我打死她
Don't shoot or I'll kill her.
把枪放下 放下
Put down your guns, put down.
小慧
Siu Wai.
狗公
Doggy!
我们…我们胜利了吗？
Have we won?
胜利了
Yes, we have.
胜利了还不分钱？
Why don't you divide the money then?
我…我那份
I... I will.
捐 捐给…
Donate... to...
狗公
Doggy!
对不起 对不起呀
Sorry...
要建立一个民主的中国 是不需要说对不起的
You needn't say sorry as we must build up a democratic China
这一次我们兄弟的死 完全是为了民运
Our men died for democratic campaign
绝对不是为了金钱
And absolutely not for money
我们决定把这些钱全部都捐给民运
So we've decided to donate all this money for it.
我这个表坏了 你修好了之后 拿到美国给我
My watch's broken down, take it to US for me after you have it fixed.
妈的 统统上车
Shit! All get in the car.
是
Yes.
喂 我已经把你的情报报告上头了
Hello, I've reported it to the seniors
为了不想有任何线索落在中方手上
In order not to let Chinese Government get any clues
你不需要把那两个大圈抓回来 把他们就地解决吧
You needn't arrest the Chinese gangsters, just solve them on spot
这个任务还包括了你那个线民
This mission includes your informer
那个王八蛋是死有余辜
He deserves to be killed!